Inventory of the C. Turner Joy Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
C. Turner Joy papers
1951-1969
1951-1954
74085
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 envelope (1.3 linear feet)
Diaries, notes, clippings, and photographs relating to the Panmunjom negotiations to end the Korean War.
Joy, C. Turner (Charles Turner), 1895-1956.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1974.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Charles Turner Joy (February 17, 1895-June 13, 1956) was a Vice Admiral in the United States Navy, the senior United Nations delegate to the Korean Armistice Conference at Kaesong and later Panmunjom from July 1951 to May 1952, and Commander Naval Forces, Far East (COMNAVFE) from August 1949 to June 1952.
Scope and Content of Collection
Includes diaries, notes, clippings, and photographs relating to the Panmunjom negotiations to end the Korean War.
United States. Navy--Officers.; Korean War, 1950-1953--Armistices.
- Working File, 1951-1953, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Meeting schedules and notes, 1951-1952
  - Korean Armistice Conference chronology and documents, 1951-1953
  - Lessons learned from the Korean War newspaper clippings, 1968-1969
- Diaries, 1951-1952 (Box 1-2)
  - Volumes 1-3 (Box 1)
  - Photocopy, page 1-185
  - Photocopy, page 186-1024 (Box 2)
- Oversize Materials, 1951 (Box 3)
  - "Charles Joy Turner, Vice Admiral, U.S. Navy Korea" album of clippings, July
  - "Navy Interdiction, Korea," Vol. 2, Vice Admiral Joy, informational booklet, January
- Photographs, undated (Envelope A)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes 46 photos and 10 negatives concerning Vice Admiral C. Turner Joy, USN, Senior Naval Officer on the Staff of the Supreme Commander, Allied Powers, Far East, and Senior UN Delegate to the Military Armistice Negotiations in Kaesong, Korea.
- Declassified U.S. Government Records, 1952, 1954 (Box 2)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover.
  - 2011 September release of records, 1952
    Memoranda and letter concerning the United Nations Command delegation in Korea.
  - 2015 August release of records, 1954
    Navy Department, Office of Naval Intelligence correspondence from Carl F. Espe to Vice Admiral Joy providing information about members of the delegation to the Armistice Conference in Korea (General Nam Il, General Hsieh Fang, and General Lee Sang Cho).